Guide to the Civil War Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Civil War collections, 1836-1960; 1836-1865; Series I
  - Gay, John O.
    John O. Gay was a soldier from Weymouth, Massachusetts, who volunteered for service around June 1864. His letters to his family during the last year of the war were mostly written from Washington, DC, where he was stationed after November 1864. While not very informative about the war, they convey the character of a religious man with strong family feeling who misses his home and family intensely. There are a few comments on Lincoln's assassination in the letters of April 1865, and some details, in passing, on the day to day life of a soldier. Two letters from his wife, Susan, are also in the collection.
    - Letters written from Fort Ethan Allen, 1864 October (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Letters written from the "Potomac River," and from Forts Craig and Reynolds in Washington, DC, 1864 November-December (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Letters written from Fort Reynolds in Washington, DC, Circa 1865 January-June (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
    - Letters from Susan A. Gay, 1865 April-May (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Gile, David Herrick (1836-1898)
    David Herrick Gile was a captain in Grant's Army of Tennessee, and aide-de-camp to General James B. McPherson. He participated in the Battles of Vicksburg and Chattanooga, and Sherman's March through Georgia and the March to the Sea. His letters often contain vivid descriptions of army life and some excellent accounts of battles. In addition to the letters, there is a family genealogy, some photographs, and some war memorabilia.
    - Correspondence, 1861-1864 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Photographs, memorabilia, etc. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Genealogy of Gile Family (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Flags, bullet (in case) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Flag, Union Jack, silk
      General
      See: Box 31A
    - Flag, United States, 37 stars, silk
  - Ingalls, William Henry Harrison (1841- )
    Consists of letters, 1861 Nov 29-1864 Mar 9, from Harrison Ingalls of South Westerlo, Albany County, New York, to members of his family while serving with the 91st New York Volunteers in Florida and Louisiana. There are also a series of letters, 1861 Apr 6-1865 Dec 2, from various family members in Michigan, Indiana, and New York to Truman Ingalls (1804-1867), Harrison's father, including letters from other family members serving in the war. These family letters contain many comments and details on war matters, local and family affairs, and domestic economy.
    - Correspondence, Ingalls, William Henry Harrison, 1861-1864 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Ingalls family, 1861-1865 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Ingalls family, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - James, Edward Christopher (1841-1901)
    The papers of Colonel Edward Christopher James consist chiefly of 107 letters written during the period August 22, 1861, to August 5, 1863, while he was with the 106th Volunteers of New York. The letters are addressed to his mother, Lucia Ripley James (1819-1901), and to his father, Amaziah Bailey James (1812-1883), in Ogdensburg, New York. The remainder of the collection includes memorabilia and photographs of family and prominent Civil War figures, many of which were taken by M. S. Brady.
    Colonel James served as acting-assistant adjutant-general of the engineer brigade of the New York 50th Volunteers during the winter of 1861-1862 and during the Peninsular Campaign (1862) was aide-de-camp on the staff of General Daniel P. Woodbury, commanding the engineering brigade in the Army of the Potomac. James made an extremely rapid rise in rank from adjutant in 1861 at the age of 20 to the rank of colonel in 1862 at the age of 21. Many of the letters deal with the trials and tribulations of command for so young an officer. Along with reflections on home, honor, and duty, the letters provide a valuable insight into Union Army life as experienced by a most impressionable young man.
    - Correspondence, 90 pages, 1861 August-December (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 110 pages, 1862 February-August (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 76 pages, 1862 September-December (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 105 pages, 1863 January-August (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Volunteer enlistment and Army commissions, 5 large documents (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Printed biographical sketch of E. C. James, 5 pages (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Printed history of Ogdensburg, New York, during the Civil War, p. 112-167 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Clipping-Obituary of E. C. James, 1 page (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Clipping, 1 page, 1861 August (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Typescript: description of papers and identification of persons mentioned in the letters, by Mrs. Philip Gray. 4 pages, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Photographs (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Loose photographs. Small carte-de-visite size. 53 items. Mostly of Civil War leaders.
    - Photograph album (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Album of 50 small photographs, mostly Civil War leaders, including duplicates of those in folder 7.
  - Jarvis, George Cyprian (1834-1901)
    Consists of letters, diaries, documents, printed material, clippings, and photographs regarding Dr. Jarvis's service during the war and with the Connecticut Infantry, 7th Regiment.
    - Correspondence, 1861-1865 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence and fragments, 1869-1901, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Diaries (2 volumes), 1864-1865 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Clippings (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lusk, William Thompson (1838-1898), correspondence, 1861 June-1863 Sep, undated (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
    Consists of letters from Lusk to members of his family.
  - Norman, William F.
    Consists of letters from Norman to his wife and some miscellaneous items.
    - Correspondence, 1862 April-1864 November (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
      See also: Box 31A
    - Correspondence, undated and miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Paddock, Elbridge E.
    Consists of correspondence, diaries, and other papers, 1862-1866, relating primarily to Paddock's duties as quartermaster with the 1st Regiment of the Connecticut Artillery.
    - Correspondence, 1864-1865 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Diaries (2 volumes), 1862 June 7-1863 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1st Connecticut Artillery
      - Quartermaster's book, 1865-1866 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Quartermaster's monthly returns, 1865 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
      - Quartermaster's requisitions, 1865 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Ration returns, 1865 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous blank forms, Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Quartermaster's general orders, 1865 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Quartermaster's ration slips, 1865 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Parmelee, Henry Spencer (1843-1902)
    Henry Spencer Parmelee was the son of Spencer Thomas Parmelee, a New Haven merchant and president of the Fair Haven and Westville Horse Railroad, which was the first street railroad in New Haven. He entered the service as a member of Company B of the 1st Connecticut Cavalry on September 8, 1862, in Bridgeport, Connecticut, and was stationed at Fort Trumbull in New London, Connecticut, for several weeks before being sent to the Baltimore and Washington, DC, areas. He served as an orderly for General Henry S. Briggs of the Army of the Potomac for some time and lost his right hand at the Battle of Sayler's Creek, Virginia.
    The correspondence consists of approximately 180 letters between Parmelee and members of his family in New Haven. Much of this correspondence is fairly routine, describing the details of camp and army life and family and social news from home. It would appear from the correspondence that Parmelee did not see much battle action himself, although there is some information on the death of his brother Lewis at Antietam. There is also some correspondence from others who were not members of the family, notably, a few letters from General Briggs.
    - Correspondence, 1862 September-1867 Mar, 1871 Nov, undated (Box 20, Folder 1-12)
    - Military passes, etc., 1863-1866 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Diary notes, 1864, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Bills, receipts, etc., 1867, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Porter, Thomas W.
    - Correspondence, 1859-1864 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Commission and discharge papers, orders, reports, printed material, and other papers, 1861-1865, undated (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
  - Rhodes, William B.
    - Journal, 1861-1864 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, miscellaneous, 1865, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Seymour, Thomas Day (1848-1907), collector, 1861-1865
    Miscellaneous papers collected by Seymour while a member of the Christian Commission in Richmond, Virginia. Eleven reports by field commanders on an engagement in the defense of Richmond between June 28 and July 2, 1862, make up half of the papers. Also included are correspondence and other papers of General John H. Winder relating to his office as provost marshal and commander of the Northern prisons in Richmond. In addition, scattered items of correspondence and official documents from departments of the Confederate States in Richmond, 1862-1865, to and from Jefferson Davis.
    - Reports on the defense of Richmond, 1862 June 28-July 2
      - Brown, General J. Thompson, 1862 July 14 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Cutts, Lieutenant Colonel A. S., 1862 July 12 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Lane, Captain John, 1862 July 12 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Massie, Lieutenant John L., 1862 July 12 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Nelson, Major William R. With two reports to Major Nelson, 1862 July 12, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Poague, William T., 1862 July 7 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Richardson, Major Charles. Three reports to Major Richardson, 1862 July 11, 12 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Papers of Major General John H. Winder
      - Correspondence, 1861 June 27-1863 June 20, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Criminal records; miscellaneous papers relating to trials and courts-martial, 1862 August 28-1863 October 14, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Confederate States of America-government documents
      - Army, 1862 March 20-1863 June 10, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Department of Justice, 1862 March 19 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Navy Department, 1863 May 21, 1864 October 6, 1865 January 27 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Senate, 1862 March 21 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Treasury Department, 1862 February 26, March 22; 1865 January 9 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - War Department, 1862 March 22; 1864 November 9 (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Printed forms, Undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Davis, Jefferson (1808-1889), President, Confederate States of America
        - Letters of transmittal from the Secretary of War (enclosures missing), 1863 February 28, April 10 (Box 31, Folder 17)
        - Letters of transmittal of the report of the Post Master general re the Trans-Mississippi Department, 1865 February 27
        - Trenholm, George A., Autograph letter signed to Jefferson Davis with an estimate for an appropriation, 1865 January 28 (Box 31, Folder 17)
        - Autograph letter signed to the Senate of the Confederate States on the appointment of E. G. Lee to Brigadier General, 1865 February 13 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Other
      - Appointments and passes, 1862 May 16-1863 February 21 (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - Memorabilia (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - Reports of the Battle of Perryville, Kentucky, 1862 Oct 8
        - Field, Colonel H. R., 1862 October 12 (Box 31, Folder 20)
        - Kelsoe, Major G. W., 1862 October 12 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Sharpe, George Henry (1828-1900)
    - Letter books (2), 1864 January-May (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Photostat of clipping regarding General Sharpe from Kingston Daily Freeman, 1937 June 5 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Warren, William H., compiler
    William H. Warren was a soldier in the 17th Regiment, Connecticut Infantry Volunteers. The regiment was organized at Bridgeport, Fairfield County, Connecticut, and was mustered on August 28, 1862. The regiment was mustered out on July 19, 1865, at Hilton Head, Beaufort County, South Carolina.
    - "William H. Warren's Experience as a Prisoner of War. Captured at Gettysburg, July 1, 1863." typescript (Box 24)
    - "The Great Rebellion, A History of the 17th Connecticut Volunteer Infantry from 1862-1866," five volumes, 1863-1865, 1873, 1880, 1882 (Box 24)
    - Diaries, one labelled "Gettysburg", 1863-1865 (Box 24)
    - Photographs, loose, of soldiers
      Arranged alphabetically by last name.
      - A-D (Box 25)
      - F-L (Box 25)
      - M-P (Box 25)
      - R-T (Box 25)
      - V-W (Box 25)
      - Group photographs, memorials, buildings (Box 25)
    - Photographs, bound, of soldiers (Box 25A)
      Bound randomly, photographs have identifications on verso, and some may duplicate loose photographs.
    - Scrapbook, clippings regarding the 17th Connecticut Volunteers (Box 26)
    - Typed volume: "Letters sent and received from members of the Seventeenth Connecticut Volunteer Regiment, 1873-1890," (Box 26)
- Civil War manuscripts, 1861-1902; Series II
  Series II, Civil War manuscripts, consists of small collections of a few items, including not only correspondence, diaries, documents, photographs, and newspapers, but also ephemera, such as poems, patriotic song lyrics, ration slips, flags, and related items. Engravings of members of President Lincoln's Cabinet are included in this series.
  - Aley, Dennis (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Anonymous (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Antietam, Maryland National Cemetery (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Arthur, B. F. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Barnes, Paul, 1902
  - Bowers, Theodore S. (1832-1866) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Brewbaker, A. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Bristol, Eugene Stuart (1843-1910) (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Brockway, C. B. correspondence from, to E. H. Little, 1861 June 16-September 30 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Butler, Benjamin Franklin (1818-1893) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Burnham, Waterman Rufus (1831- ) (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Consists of correspondence (22 items) received by Burnham, a cotton manufacturer and Sunday School teacher from Uncasvile, Connecticut, from several of his former students regarding their activities as soldiers in the Federal Army during the Civil War in Virginia, South Carolina, and Florida. Correspondents include Henry T. Phillips (Lieutenant, 21st Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers), George R. Sanders (a negro hospital attendent, 3rd Regiment, Corps d'Afrique), Frederick E. Shalk (Sergeant, Co. E, 14th Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers), Edward Sharp (Private, Co. H, 7th Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers), John E. Sisson (Co. B, 3rd Brigade, 6th Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers), and David Sanders (Private, Co. H, 7th Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers).
  - Cahill, Thomas W. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "Cheer for the Banner", Circa 1865 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Lyrics for a patriotic song in a program of graduation exercises for an unidentified school during the Civil War period. Includes lyrics for additional patriotic songs and poems, "Columbia, the Land of the Brave" and "Ellsworth's Avengers."
  - Chickahominy River: map (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Clark, Jonah Francis (d.1863) (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Conely, William S. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Confederate States of America (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut Infantry. 15th Regiment (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Cook, William, "The Bank" (Box 27, Folder 17)
    Poems about the war with crayon drawings bound in.
  - Cooke, Giles B. (Major, Confederate States of America) (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Curtice, William (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Dawley, James B., correspondence, 1862-1865 (Box 27, Folder 20-23)
  - Delaware Infantry. 2nd Regiment, payroll and reports (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Flint, Henry M. (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Fox, George (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - French, Samuel Gibbs (1818-1910) (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Gaffney, P. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Geer, Charles Franklin, correspondence (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Gill family
    Of the 62 items in this collection, 52 are letters from three brothers, Henry B. Gill, George T. Gill, and William H. Gill, written while serving in the Union Army to their brother, John T. Gill, a dealer in flour and produce in New Haven. There are also a few letters to other members of the family, and some correspondence and documents from others relating to the war. The letters, sent from camps in Virginia, North Carolina, and Florida, discuss camp life, troop movements, the course of the war, provisions for the troops, and the private arrangements for trade made by the brothers who imported goods for resale from New Haven. There are also some fragments of poetry, possibly written by John T. Gill
    - Gill, George T., 1862-1863, 1865, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Gill, Henry B., 1862-1865 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Gill, William H., 1863-1866 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1865, 1867, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Gilman, Charles O., power of attorney to vote (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Glines, Henry C., 1861-1863 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Correspondence and a three pocket diary, 7th Regiment Connecticut Volunteers.
  - Griffith, T. J. R., letter, 1862 April 20 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Grosvenor, Samuel E., photocopies of 1864 diary (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Hall, J. C. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Harman, Michael G. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Harvey, Delia A. P. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Higgins, George W. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Holden, Thomas M. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Hubbard, Robert (1826-1898)
    Robert Hubbard was a physician and a commissioned surgeon of the 17th Regiment of the Connecticut Infantry (Volunteers) in 1862. The letters are almost all to his wife in Bridgeport, Connecticut, and describe his daily life, comments on the political situation, and on the progress of the war. Of particular interest are his full accounts of the battles of Gettysburg (1863 Jul 1-3), Lookout Mountain (1863 Nov 24), Missionary Ridge (1863 Nov 25), and Ringgold (1863 Nov 27) in which he was active as surgeon to the troops. With the letters are also obituaries and biographical information.
    - Correspondence, original, 1862 April-1864 January (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
    - Transcriber's notes (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, typescript, 1862 September-1864 January (Box 32, Folder 9-12)
    - Biographical material (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Jacoby, W. H. correspondence from, to E. H. Little, 1862 November 22 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Jones, Abijah (1813-1863) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Keiser, Leonidas (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Knickerbocker, Ada (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Leonard, John (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Lewis, C. A. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Lewis, S. N. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - [Lincoln, Abraham (1809-1865)] (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Lowndes, R. H. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - McChesney, James M. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - McKay, Donald (1810-1880) (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Meade, George Gordon (1815-1872) (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Mee, Patrick (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Miner, James (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Mitchell, George, C. B. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Mock, Martin Luther (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Mosby, John Singleton (1833-1916) (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Nelson, H. P. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Nettleton-Baldwin family
    The 22 letters in this collection are either by or to members of a family from Milford, Connecticut. A. P. Baldwin and his wife, Annie, live in New York City where they have a store, and their nine letters are addressed to his mother, Mrs. D. L. Baldwin, and his sister, Lotte [i.e. Charlotte A.] in Milford. Their letters, beginning on April 22, 1861, describe the events in New York City following the news of the firing on Fort Sumter, with reports on the sermons they heard on the following Sunday. The correspondence between the women includes family news and domestic arrangements. There is also a group of ten letters written by Lewis Nettleton to Lotte [his fiancée?] reporting the life of the ordinary soldier and commenting on the events of the war.
    - Correspondence from A. P. and Annie Baldwin, 1861 April 22-1862 November 13 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence from Lewis Nettleton to Lotte Baldwin and to his sister; one letter from Lotte Baldwin to Lewis Nettleton; 2 miscellaneous letters to Lotte Baldwin; and 9 envelopes (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Nettleton, Gilbert and Camp, 1863 October 1 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - New York Artillery. 13th Regiment (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Nicholson, Robert Livingston (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Otto, William Tod (1816-1905), invalid pension document, 1866 April 9 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Artillery. 3rd Regiment, provision and ration slips, 1864-1865 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania Infantry. 28th Regiment, discharge document, 1865 July 18 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Phelps, Dallas S., letter to friend, 1864 March 31 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Photographs-miscellaneous-Confederate, Undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Photographs-miscellaneous-Union, Undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Pitkin, James, letter to his brother and sister, n.y. September 20 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Press, A. A., 1863 January 10-February 8 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    Letters to his brother and sister.
  - Sawyer, O. G., letter, 1862 July 8 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Shaler, Brigadier General Alexander, U.S. Volunteers, copy of journal writtten while he was a prisoner of war in a Confederate camp, 1864 May 3-August 9 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Shoemaker, Michael, letter declining invitation to 20th reunion of the Army of the Cumberland, Undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Shriver, William M., 3 diaries, 1862 February-1863 December (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Sill, H., letter to father, 1864 January 18 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Rily, letters to cousin Emma, 1863-1864 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Sullly, Alfred (1821-1879), letter of recommendation, 1862 July 25 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Taylor, James [Kentucky], letter re construction of a bridge, 1863 April 19 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Thayer, John Milton (1820-1906), letters to his wife, letter written by him while serving as senator from Nebraska, 1861-1863, 1868 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - United States Army, District of Eastern Virginia, "Roll of Deserters from the Rebel Army," 1865 Feb-Mar; special orders, 1864-1865 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - United States Army, 3rd Infantry, report of troop movements, 1863 October (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Lincoln's Cabinet-engravings
    - Bates, Edward (1793-1869). Engraving by Max Rosenthal, signed "Edw. Bates" in the plate, inlaid., 1892 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Blair, Montgomery (1813-1883). Engraving, signed in the plate, inlaid. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Cameron, Simon (1799-1889). Engraving, signed in the plate, inlaid. Engraved for the Rebellion Record. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Chase, Salmon Portland (1808-1873). Engraving, signed in the plate. Mounted. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Dennison, William (1815-1882). Engraving, signed in the plate, inlaid. 2 copies. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Fessenden, William Pitt (1806-1869). Engraving by J.C. Buttre from a daguerreotype. Signed "W.P. Fessendent." Inlaid. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - McCulloch, Hugh (1808-1895). Engraving, signed in the plate. For Putnam's Magazine. Inlaid. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Seward, William Henry (1801-1872). Engraving, signed in the plate. Inlaid. Engraved by J.C. Buttre. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Seward, William Henry (1801-1872). Engraving, signed in the plate. Inlaid. Engraved by A.H. Ritchie. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Smith, Caleb Blood (1808-1864). Engraving, signed in the plate. Inlaid. Engraved from a mezzotint by P.M. Whelpley, for the American Review. (Box 30, Folder 19)